{
    "id": "32d3b00a39ce40bdac055c1e4f48bb36",
    "title": "Conditional Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I find your wallet, I ………………………… it to you.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will send",
                "would send",
                "would have sent"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If she …………………… her lessons diligently, she would get a much better score.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "learns",
                "learned",
                "had learned"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If she …………………….. your true identity, you will be in trouble.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "discovers",
                "discovered",
                "had discovered"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you aren’t busy today, we …………………….. for a drive.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "can go",
                "could go",
                "could have gone"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you don’t quit smoking, you ………………………….. cancer.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will have",
                "would have",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had sent the money in the morning, she …………………………….. it in the evening.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will receive",
                "would receive",
                "would have received"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had gone to university, I ………………………….. journalism.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will study",
                "would study",
                "would have studied"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had been more careful, you ……………………………… this mistake.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will not make",
                "would not make",
                "would not have made"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had heard the forecast, I ………………………….. an umbrella with me.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will carry",
                "would carry",
                "would have carried"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you started earlier, you …………………………. the bus.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will not miss",
                "would not miss",
                "would not have missed"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ……………………….. guests, I will cook something delicious for them.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "have had"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had waited, you ………………………….. a better offer.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might + have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will receive",
                "would receive",
                "would have received"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}